Guide to the William Miller Abrahams Papers, ca. 1945-1998
Department of Special Collections
William Miller Abrahams Papers,
ca. 1945-1998
Special Collections M1125
Abrahams, William Miller, 1919-
42 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Peter Stansky, 2000.
Biography
A poet and a novelist, William Abrahams became one of the leading literary editors in the American publishing scene. He worked with many renowned writers including Joyce Carol Oates, Lillian Hellman, Diane Johnson, Brian Moore, Thomas Flanagan, and Pauline Kael. Beginning as a poet, Abrahams released his first novel Interval in Carolina (1945) to good reviews. He followed with By the Beautiful Sea (1947) and Imperial Waltz (1954) before beginning a career in editing for Atlantic Monthly Press in 1963. In 1965 he began supervising the O. Henry Awards, editing annual anthologies of the best entries, which he continued until his retirement in 1996. Abrahams also produced four non-fiction works that he co-authored with historian Peter Stansky, Journey to the Frontier; Two Roads to the Spanish Civil War (1966), The Unknown Orwell (1972), Orwell: The Transformation (1980), and London's Burning: Life, Death, and Art in the Second World War (1994).
In addition to his editorial career, Abrahams also served as a trustee for the Lillian Hellman-Dashiell Hammett Literary Estates, and as a member of the William Saroyan Foundation. Abrahams' longstanding relationship with Hellman as both editor and friend, subsequently led to his being named official biographer for Hellman in 1983. Abrahams worked sporadically on the Hellman biography until his death in 1998, never reaching completion due to his extensive editorial commitments and deteriorating health.
Scope and Content
The William Abrahams Papers include material on books that Abrahams edited under his own imprint for such presses as the Atlantic Monthly Press, Holt Rhinehart and Winston, and E. P. Dutton. The papers contain working drafts, typescripts, research notes, and correspondence. Financial reports and correspondence relating to his service as literary trustee are also present, along with research files on both Lillian Hellman and Dashiell Hammett. Additionally, a collection of the books Abrahams edited during his distinguished career, and the texts he co-authored with historian Peter Stansky are available.
The papers are divided into 4 series: 1. Editorial Files, 2. Trustee Files, 3. Hellman Biography Material, 4. Personal Files.
Wherever Abrahams' original arrangement of materials was encountered, the order was retained. A substantial amount of the material, however, showed little sign of a concise intellectual schema, and therefore required an imposed order. Where possible, arrangement notes for the specific series will indicate which portions retain Abrahams' original arrangement and which reflect an ordering imposed by the processor.
Series Description and Container Listing
- Series 1. Editorial files
  Within the Editorial Series, the Author files subseries is arranged in alphabetical order, with typescript material, correspondence, editorial material, and book reviews gathered separately within the folders. Abrahams generally bundled all material indiscriminately within large brown envelopes labeled by author and book, possibly after an editorial project was completed. The current arrangement represents a minimal attempt to impose an order where none was apparent. Typescript material may be original or photocopied, full or partial drafts, galleys, or proofs. Correspondence typically contains exchanges between the author, the author's agent, and Abrahams. Editorial material can consist of internal publishing company memorandums, sample pages, proof photographs of author, book jacket samples or proofs, lists of editorial changes, research notes, and other material related to the editing process. Book reviews are typically photocopied, and other photocopied articles concerning the author or book may be included here. The Correspondence subseries generally follows the order imposed by Abrahams, with the exception of letters found mixed in with other unrelated material being added to the files in proper chronological and alphabetical order.
  - Subseries A. Authors
    - Apffel, Edmund. Last days at St. Saturn's: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bailey, Paul. An immaculate mistake, 1992: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Barker, Pat. The eye in the door: correspondence, editorial material. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Barker, Pat. The eye in the door: photocopies and faxes of reviews, newspaper clippings. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Barker, Pat. The ghost road: correspondence, editorial material. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Barker, Pat. The ghost road: photocopies of reviews, newspaper clippings. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Barker, Pat. Regeneration: correspondence, editorial material. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Barker, Pat. Regeneration: photocopies and faxes of reviews, newspaper clippings. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Barker, Pat.: correspondence, faxed proposals for three novels. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Battiscombe Georgina. Christina Rossetti: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bell, Susan Groag. Between worlds: ts of chapter "Looking after Puli;" corespondence, editorial material,photocopies of reviews (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Belland, F.W. The True Sea: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Berthoud, Roger. The life of Henry Moore: photocopied ts of partial first draft (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Berthoud, Roger. The life of Henry Moore: photocopy of partial, corrected ts (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Berthoud, Roger. The life of Henry Moore: photocopy of revised ts, pp. 1-6, 12-126 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Berthoud, Roger. The life of Henry Moore: photocopy of revised ts, pp.127- 272 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Berthoud, Roger. The life of Henry Moore: photocopy of revised ts, pp. 273-399, p. 314 missing (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Berthoud, Roger. The life of Henry Moore: correspondence (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Berthoud, Roger. The life of Henry Moore: photocopy of synopsis, editorial material and correspondence,photocopies of reviews, newspaper clippings (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Bessie, Alvah.: miscelllaneous ts from Hesitation waltz, One for my baby (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bessie, Alvah. One for my baby: correspondence about book and other projects (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bessie, Alvah. One for my baby: editorial material, photocopies of reviews, newspaper clippings (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bondy, Ruth. the emissary: correspondence (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Bondy, Ruth. The emissary: editorial material, photocopies of reviews and articles (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Brancatelli, Robert. The maiden ape: photocopy of ts, submission letter and reply (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Capps Walter H. God Bless America: photocopy of ts, pp. 1-154, correspondence (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Carroll, Peter N. Famous in America: photocopied ts, pp. 1-136 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Carroll, Peter N. Famous in America: photocopied ts, pp. 137-307 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Carroll, Peter N. Famous in America: photocopied ts, pp. 308-484 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Carroll, Peter N. The best years of our lives: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews, newspaper clippings, some photocopied ts (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Carroll, Peter N. The best years of our lives: correspondence, editorial material for paperback edition (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Clare, George. Before the wall: correspondence (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Clare, George. Before the wall: editorial material, photocopies of reviews, newspaper clippings (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Clare, George. Last waltz in Vienna: correspondence, photographs of author, and author's family (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Clare, George. Last waltz in Vienna: editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Cole, Tom.: correspondence, photocopy of sample short story, samples of daughter's, Sarah Cole, writings (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Coppel, Alfred. The Marburg Chronicles: two photocopies of outline and notes, correspondence, photocopy of newspaper article (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Any four women could rob the bank of Italy: ts, two pages, ts, pp 1-57 with correspondence (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Any four women could rob the bank of Italy: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Strangers and pilgrims: correspondence (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Strangers and pilgrims: editorial material, photocopies of reviews, photographs of author, photographs taken by author (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Torregreca: ts of introduction, correspondence 1967-1970, book jacket proofs (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Where it all began, Italy 1954: ts, pp 1-126, includes proposed revision of beginning (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Where it all began, Italy 1954: ts, pp 1-111 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Where it all began, Italy 1954: ts, pp 112-258 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Where it all began, Italy 1954: ts, pp 149-160, miscellaneous ts, correspondence (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Where it all began, Italy 1954: ts, pp 96-174 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Where it all began, Italy 1954: correspondence, photographs of author (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Women of the shadows: editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Women of the shadows: correspondence, editorial material (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Craig, Patricia.: photocopied ts of proposal for biography of Brian Moore (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Cukor, George.: correspondence,, copy of transcript for possible book of memoirs (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Dangerfield, George. The damnable question: correspondence, editorial material including partial ts of synopsis, photocopies of reviews (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Davis, Terry. Vision quest: one letter of correspondence (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Davison, Jane. The fall of a doll's house: correspondence (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Davison, Jane. The fall of a doll's house: photocopies of chapter outlines, photocopy of introduction, ts (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Davison, Jane. The fall of a doll's house: editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Dillon, Millicent. After Egypt, Isadora Duncan and Mary Cassat: correspondence (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Dillon, Millicent. After Egypt, Isadora Duncan and Mary Cassat: editorial material [one of two] (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Dillon, Millicent. After Egypt, Isadora Duncan and Mary Cassat: editorial material [two of two] (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Dillon, Millicent. After Egypt, Isadora Duncan and Mary Cassat: photocopies of reviews, ts proposals for biography of Paul Bowles, ts of two short stories, miscellaneous correspondence (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Dillon, Millicent. A little original sin: photocopies of reviews (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Dillon, Millicent.The dance of the mothers: editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Dillon, Millicent.: ts of several short stories, some correspondence (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Dundy, Elaine: Finch, bloody Finch: correspondence, correspondence and proposal for biography of Elvis Presley (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Dundy, Elaine: Finch, bloody Finch: editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Egremont, Max. Painted Lives: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Emmerson, John. The Japanese thread: photocopy of ts, several chapters, photocopies of articles by author (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Emmerson, John. The Japanese thread: correspondence, photograph of author and wife[?] (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Emmerson, John. The Japanese thread: editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Faust, Irvin. The year of the hot jock and other stories: photocopied galley proof (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Faust, Irvin. The year of the hot jock and other stories: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together, part I, her way: photocopied ts [one of three] (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together, part II, his way: photocopied ts [two of three] (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together: photocopied ts of recipes [three of three] (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together: photocopied ts of recipes (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together: correspondence, copyedited ts, pp 1-138 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together:copyedited ts, pp 139-249 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Feibleman, Peter S., and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together: copyedited ts, pp 250-333 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The dangerous edge of things: photocopied ts of proposal [two copies] (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The dangerous edge of things: correspondence, ts proposal with editing (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The dangerous edge of things: photocopied ts chapters I and II (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The end of the hunt: photocopied ts pp 38-42, 1085-1148,some loose pp, photocopies of ts for outline (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The end of the hunt: correspondence, editorial material (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The end of the hunt: photocopies of reviews (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The tenants of time: photocopied ts synopsis of "The unforgiving iron," original title (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The tenants of time: photocopied ts pp 96-163, 412-470, several loose pp, photocopies of essays by Flanagan, photocopy of lecture introduction bt William M. Chace (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The tenants of time: correspondence (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The tenants of time: editorial material [one of two] (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The tenants of time: editorial material [two of two] (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. The tenants of time: photocopies of reviews (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Flanagan, Thomas.: photocopy of essay by author, photographs of author, critical essay of author's work, American-Irish historical society presentation folder (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Flanagan, Thomas. unidentified novel, pp 1-118, mostly ts, some photocopied ts (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Fox, Ted. The last great year: photocopied ts of proposal (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Futcher, Jane, and Conover, Bob. Marin, the place, the people: photocopied ts of part II,correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Garfield, Patricia. Pathway to ecstasy: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of sample writings, photocopy of review (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Gebler, Carlo. August in July: photocopied edited ts pp 1-113, copy of reader's report (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Gebler, Carlo. August in July: photocopied edited ts, pp 114-223 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Giddings, Joshua. Dissipative structures: photocopies of ts, several versions of chapter I, chapter II (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Giddings, Joshua. photocopy of Wallace Stegner fellowship application, photocopied ts of short stories, poetry (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Giddings, Joshua.The old girl: photocopied ts of author's statement, ts of chapter I, correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Gleason, Ralph J. Celebrating the Duke: ts of contents page, correspondence, editoral material, photocopies of reviews (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Gleason, Ralph J. Celebrating the Duke: photocopy of interview transcript with Studs Terkel, photocopies of newspaper obituaries (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Gleason, Ralph J.: photocopies of newspaper columns and essays by author (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Goodman, Eric. High on th energy: photocopied ts of plot synopsis, correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Greenleaf, Victoria. A handful of ashes: correspondence, photocopied ts of book synopsis, chapter outlines,sample chapters (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Hansen, Eric. Stranger in the forest: correspondence, photocopy of proposal and sample chapters (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Haring, Firth. The woman who went away: photocopied ts of brief description, corrspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Harris, David. South of the border: ts of plot synopsis, correspondence (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Hastings, Selina. Nancy Mitford: correspondence, photocopied incomplete galley proofs (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Hastings, Selina. Nancy Mitford: editoral material, photocopies of reviews (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: blue line proofs, some editorial annotations (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: photocopied master proof with editing (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: photocopied galley proofs, two copies with correspondence (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: editorial material including photocopied ts of replacement pages, carbon lists of changes and research requests (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: photocopied ts, carbon and photocopied lists of editorial changes (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: photocopy of proofed pages (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: masterproof with transmittal slip (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: photocopied ts, edited, correspondence listing editorial changes (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: photocopied ts and carboned ts (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: correspondence (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: photocopied ts (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Maybe: photocopies of reviews (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Pentimento: photocopied, corrected ts of Julia, Willy, Turtle, Arthur Cowan, with correspondence (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Pentimento: carboned and photocopied lists of editorial changes, photocopied ts of Bethe, Ullage (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Pentimento: photocopied galley proofs, pp 1-147 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Pentimento: photocopied galley proofs, pp 148-297 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Pentimento: correspondence, photocopied ts of Richard Poirer's introduction, photocopies of reviews (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: original ts, pp 1-89 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: original ts, some carbon, pp 90-123, extra pp (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: carbon copied ts, some corrections, pp 1-123, some random pp. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: photocopied galley proofs, photograph inserts (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: photocopied ts of Gary Will's introduction, ts of editor's notes on introduction (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: ts of editor's note, correspondence, editorial material, research material, photocopies of photographs for possible use in book (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: photocopied ts, single page of ts editorial corrections (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: photocopied ts, includes title pages and Gary Will's introduction (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: correspondence (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: editorial material (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: photocopies of reviews, interviews, articles (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: correspondence and photocopies of articles regarding Diana Trilling's essay on Hellman (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: photocopied ts of Hellman's acceptance remarks upon receipt of the McDowell Medal Award, photocopied ts of John Hersey's introduction for same, photocopy of Hellman's review of Ray, Gordon N.: H.G. Wells and Rebecca West (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Three: master galleys and galley proofs of Richard Poirer's introduction (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Three: several sets of incomplete galleys and galley proofs (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Three: galleys, jacket proofs, with correspondence (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Three: copyedited ts with correspondence and notes (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Three: photocopied ts of Richard Poirer's introduction, edited, photocopied ts of introduction (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Three: correspondence, editorial material, photocopied galleys (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Three: carbon and photocopied ts of introduction and notes to follow specific pieces (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Three: photocopied ts of Richard Poirer's introduction, photocopied ts of notes to follow pieces (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Hellman, Lillian. An unfinished woman: photocopied and carboned ts of first chapters (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Hellman, Lillian. An unfinished woman: photocopied ts, pp 1-155 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Hellman, Lillian. An unfinished woman: photocopied ts, pp 156-275 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Hellman, Lillian. An unfinished woman: photocopied ts, pp 1-137 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Hellman, Lillian. An unfinished woman: photocopied ts, pp 138-275 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Hellman, Lillian. An unfinished woman: carbon and photocopied ts, chapters IX-XVI, letter from Hellman (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Hellman, Lillian. An unfinished woman: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Hill, Carol. The eleven million mile high dancer: correspondence, editorial material (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Hill, Carol. The eleven million mile high dancer: editorial material, photocopiues of reviews (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Hillaby, John. Journey home: correspondence, editorial material, photocopies of reviews (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Hough, Richard. One boy's war: correspondence (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Howard, Donald Roy. Chaucer: photocopied ts, part I, chapters I-V (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Cornelisen, Ann. Any four women could rob the bank of Italy: photocopy of galleys [legal size] (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Feibleman, Peter, and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together: corrected galley proofs [legal size] (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Feibleman, Peter, and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together: front page layout and proof, ts of index [legal size] (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Feibleman, Peter, and Hellman, Lillian. Eating together: galley proof master set with all changes [legal size] (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: galley proofs [legal size] (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Hellman, Lillian. Scoundrel time: galleys [legal size] (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Ingram, Kevin. Rebel: photocopied galley proofs, pp 1-141 [legal size] (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Howard, Donald Roy. Chaucer: photocopied ts, chapters 15-17, foreword, chapter 8, part of chapter 15 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Howard, Donald Roy. Chaucer: photocopied ts, chapter II (Box 23, Folder 2)